Abey E Mathews

abeyemathews@gmail.com +91 9961281024



Experience Summary

13 years of experience in **System/ Network** Administration, Technical Consulting,

Networking, Troubleshooting system and Network problem, Server Management, Cloud Infrastructure

Industry exposure include

- IT
- Healthcare
- Social Service
- Training

Companies include

- Malankara Social Service Society (MSSS), India
- Bevat Health Care and Industrial Technologies, India
- ARAS MEDICAL DEVICES &
 EQUIPMENTS CO LLC
 . UAE
- Infodawn.India

Core Skills

- Organizational Awareness
- Advanced Technical Expertise
- Flexibility and Problem Solving
- System Administration
- Windows and Linux OS
- Troubleshooting
- Active Directory
- Firewall
- Server Management
- Backup
- RAID
- DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP
- Group Policy
- VPN
- Router Configuration
- Email Migration
- AWS
- Azure
- Office 365

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA)

Professional Summary

System/Network Administrator experienced in networking, managing server infrastructures and data-center operations across Linux and Windows OS platforms. Effectively plan, install, configure and optimize IT infrastructures to achieve high availability and performance. Highly efficient in technical leadership, computer technology, and business-critical management.

Expertise in networking concepts, TCP/IP protocol, knowledge of firewall setup and administration, VPN, Active directory & group policies, DNS, DHCP and quality of service. 4+ years of experience with Microsoft Office 365, especially migrated other imap mailboxes to O365.Knowledge in managing cloud platforms like Microsoft Azure, AWS, Google Cloud.

Troubleshot system and network problems, diagnosed and solved network, hardware and software faults, in timely and cost-efficient manner. Monitored and maintained Computer network systems without any down time.

Proven diagnostic abilities with attention to detail and ability to work effectively in a fast-paced environment.

Professional Experience:

Freelance

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala [June 2009 – Present]

Responsibilities:

- Remote Server Management both Windows and Linux (CentOS/Ubuntu)
 - Managing Web Servers Apache, Nginx, Tomcat etc.
- Providing and Managing VPS/Dedicated Server, Web Hosting with cPanel/ WHM and Plesk Panels, Domain Registration.
- PHP MySQL, Application Server Monitoring.
- Migrate IMAP mailboxes to Microsoft 365/Google Workspace
- Attending Azure product training from Microsoft.
- Website Design and Development especially for E-Commerce Websites with Elastic search.
- Manage and Design Website based on CMS (Joomla, WordPress).
- Integrating HTML, CSS Templates with CMS.
- Technical Consulting.

Current Projects

Freelance Projects

- Managing Linux and Windows VPS for Fagor Automation, India, Elioenai Technologies-India
- Develop and Manage E-Commerce Website for Italian Lights, Dubai
- Develop and Manage LMS Website for Global Techboom, USA
- Managing Web Server for Eurasia Holidays-India, Musaliar Institute of Management-India, Koss Global, Malankara Library-India, Western Education Center-Sharjah, Explore Education-Dubai

Malankara Social Service Society (MSSS)

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala [June 2018 - Present]

System Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Monitor network communication
- Implement the policies for the use of the computer system and network
- Technical support for both Hardware and Software issues
- Technical support to all Windows Win 2008/2012 servers. Win 7,8,10 clients
- Active directory & group policies, DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP, IIS.
- Troubleshoot hardware issues.
- User administration (setup and maintaining accounts)
- Maintaining server and client systems
- Verifying peripherals are working properly
- Quickly arrange repair for hardware in occasion of hardware failure
- Monitor system performance
- Install and upgrade software's
- Backup solutions
- Monitor network communication
- Update system as soon as new version of OS and application software
- Setup security policies for users.
- Managing Aadhaar Fingerprint, Attendance device, biometric attendance system, CC Camera
- Website Updation.
- Updating the latest news in a social network such as Fb, Twitter, Youtube

Projects:

 Entire Networking of YUVA KERALA Project under Athijeevanam Keraliyam Scheme unded by Govt of Kerala, facilitated by Kudumbashree at MSSS

Bevat Health Care and Industrial Technologies

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala [July 2017 - June 2018]

IT Coordinator

Responsibilities:

- Technical support for IT Department (PBX System, CC Camera, VPN Router, ERP SYSTEM connectivity) of the Aras Group of Companies
- Resolved hardware and software issues on PCs, Laptop, and Printers
- Troubleshot windows system and network problems, diagnosed and solved network, hardware & software faults
- Web Designing, Developed Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) for BEVAT Healthcare, SEO for the Bevat Website
- Designed brochures, catalogues, submitted e-tender using digital signature in windows

Projects:

- Implemented VPN connectivity from Trivandrum Office to Dubai Office
- Configured VPN Router- Draytek (using Dyndns), Connected IP Phone (Yealink) to Dubai office Made access to cc-camera of Trivandrum in Dubai Office
- Website designed & developed for Bevat Healthcare URL: www.bevathealthcare.com

ARAS MEDICAL DEVICES & EQUIPMENTS CO LLC

Dubai, UAE [February 2015 - June 2017]

IT Coordinator

Responsibilities:

- Complete responsibility of the IT Department of the Aras Group of Companies at Sharjah, Abu Dhabi and Dubai
- Technical support to all Windows Win 2008/2012 servers, Win 7,8,10 clients, PBX system, PCs, Laptops, Printers
- and Photocopiers. Installing and configuring Computer hardware operating systems (Windows & Linux)
- Active Directory and controlled IT user accounts
- Group policies, DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP, IIS
- Worked on email solutions such as office 2016(Outlook) / Office 365
- Managed Antivirus products in both servers and clients
- Backup solutions such as Microsoft backup and NAS Storage backup
- Resolved hardware and software issues on PCs, Laptop, Printers & Photocopiers
- Monitored and maintained Computer network system
- Troubleshot system and network problems and diagnosed and solved network, hardware & software faults
 - Any other duties related to IT department, as required by the Management time to time, including Biomedical & Electronics Equipment's installation
- Web Designing, Support and Maintenance services

Projects:

- Entire Networking (Design & Implementation) of an office at Abu Dhabi (Hill-Floor Equipments)
- Configured VPN Router- Draytek (using Dyndns), Configured IP PBX Systems (Yealink), IP Phone (Yealink),
- Installation of Network Switch including Rack, Installed Access Point (For extending the Wi-Fi access), configured
- Configured Windows Server Connectivity from head office (Dubai) for the purpose of ERP System.Complete installation of CC Camera (CP Plus)
- Implemented VPN connectivity between Aras Medical Devices and its sister concerns (6 offices in total) at
- Dubai Sharjah and Abu Dhabi.
- Purchased, Configured and Installed hardware (Rack Server with RAID Storage) and software (Windows Server 2012) for the ERP System
- End to end network installation of Nurse Call System (Indigocare) at Burjeel Hospital Abu Dhabi

Infodawn Pathanamthitta, Kerala [January 2010 - December 2014]

Pathanamthitta, Kerala [January 2010 - December 2014]

System Administrator

Responsibilities:

- Tested, Implemented & configured software /website
- Provided End User training
- Worked on Active Directory and controlled IT user accounts
- Troubleshot technical problems and implemented solutions
- Upgraded system both at workstation and Server level
- Purchased IT Equipment's and software's in line within agreed budgets
- Hosted and Maintained websites

Areas of Expertise:

- Packaging Windows Installer, Installation & Training
- Microsoft Windows and Linux Operating Systems
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Desktop and Server Support
- Computer networks and TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP
- Active Directory

Projects:

- Entire Networking of Infodawn office Pathanamthitta.
- Purchased, Assembled, Installed and Configured Windows server 2008 with Active Directory and Client Systems (Windows 7)

Academic Records

- Master of Computer Applications (MCA) Sikkim Manipal University (2017 2021)
- Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) Sikkim Manipal University (2011-2014)
- Professional Diploma in Network Engineering Keltron (A Gov. of Kerala Undertaking) (2011-2012)
- Computer Hardware and Networking Ministry of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises, Government of India Training in E.S.D.P (2011)
- Certificate Course in Digital Still Photography C-DIT(Training Centre under the Government of Kerala)
 Off-Campus (2011)
- Diploma In Web Design & Development C-DIT(Training Centre under the Government of Kerala) Off-Campus (2011)
- Master Diploma in Electronic Design Automation Course Certificate CADD Center Training Services (2010)
- B.Tech (M.G UNIVERSITY) Electronics And Communication Mount Zion College Of Engg.Kadammanitta Course Certificate (2004-2008)
- Plus Two with Computer Science from Board of Higher Secondary Education Kerala ST. THOMASHSS, THIRUMOOLAPURAM (2002-2004)
- SSLC Metropolitan Higher Secondary School, Puthencavu (2001-2002)

Personal Particulars

Full Name : Abey E Mathews
DOB : 09 Aug 1986
Marital Status : Married

Languages Known : English; Malayalam; Hindi